Finding Aid for Tom Van Zoeren oral history collection, 1860s-2011
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Oral histories, photos, and other historic materials from the Sleeping Bear Dunes region, digital files, originally on 1 hard drive, USB connection
  - Historic Images 1860s-2010s
    - Sleeping Bear Dunes Region 1860s-2010s
      - Port Oneida 1860s-2010s, .ZIP files
        - Burfiend, Carsten Farm
          - Taro Yamasaki Burfiend Photos
        - Burfiend, John Farm
        - Burfiend Peter and Jenny Farm
          - General images
          - George Burfiend Collection
        - Dechow Farm Photos
          - General images
          - Alice Van Zoeren Dechow Farm Photos
          - Robert Klett Collection
        - Tracy Watson Collection
        - Eckerdt George Farm
        - Eckerdt Henry Farm
          - Alice Van Zoeren Eckerdt Henry Farm Photos
          - Eckerdt Henry Farm Miscellaneous
          - Marilyn Eckerdt Collection Copies
          - Midge Jesko Collection
            - General images and notes
            - Jesko Collection Documents
          - Tom Van Zoeren Eckerdt Farm Photos
        - Goffar Farm
          - General images
          - David Ritter Collection (Goffar letters)
          - Jack Barratt Collection
        - Kelderhouse, Thomas Farm
          - General images
          - Carol Allen Collection
            - Documents
            - Photos
          - Laura Weathers Collection
          - Lucille Barratt Collection
        - Kelderhouse, William Farm
          - General images
          - Charlotte Groesser Collection
          - Leon Kelderhouse Collection
          - Ruth Lambkin Collection
        - Lawr Farm
        - Miller, Carsten Farm
          - Lucille Barratt Collection
          - Taro Yamasaki Photos
        - Miller, Fred and Ellen Farm
          - General images
          - Ellen Miller Recipes
          - Paula Jones Collection
          - Robert Adair Collection
        - Millington Farm
        - North Unity School, Laura Basch Collection
        - Olsen, Charles Farm
          - General images
          - Doris Brammer Collection
          - Grace Dickinson Photos
          - Lorraine Mason Collection
          - Modern Photos
          - NPS File Photos
          - PHSB photos
          - Sally Weir Collection
          - X Collection
        - Olsen, Everett Farm
        - Olsen George Farm
          - A Van Zoeren Olsen George
          - Grace Dickinson
          - Laura Basch Collection
        - Olsen, Ole Farm
          - General images
          - Laura Basch Collection
          - Leelanau Historical Society
          - Tom Van Zoeren Olsen Ole Farm Photos
        - Port Oneida Miscellaneous
          - General images
          - Lucille Barratt Collection
          - Pt Oneida Misc-Laura Basch Collection
          - Tom Van Zoeren Pt Oneida Misc Photos
        - Port Oneida School
          - General images
          - Leonard Thoreson Collection
        - Schmidt Farm and Family
          - General images
          - A Van Zoeren Schmidt
          - Tom Van Zoeren Schmidt Farm Photos
        - Thoreson Farm
          - Alice Van Zoeren Thoreson Farm Photos
          - Grace Dickinson Thoreson Farm Photo
          - Leonard Thoreson Collection
          - Tom Van Zoeren Photos
        - Warner, August Farm, Tom Van Zoeren Photos
        - Watkins Family, Crane Collection
        - Weaver Farm
          - A Van Zoeren Weaver
          - Grace Dickinson Weaver Farm
          - Tom Van Zoeren Weaver Farm Photos
        - Werner, Frederick Farm
          - Anna Miller Collection
          - A Van Zoeren Werner Frederick Farm Photos
          - Charles Miller Family Collection
          - Grace Dickinson Werner Fred Farm Photos
          - Taro Yamasaki Photos
          - Tom Van Zoeren Werner Fred Farm Photos
          - Werner Fred Farm-NPS file images
        - Werner, Richard Farm
          - Merlene Richardson Photo Collection
          - Miscellaneous Photos
      - Other Areas, 1890-circa 2010, .ZIP file
        - General images
        - Alfred Mason Collection
        - Empire Museum Collection
        - Leelanau Historical Society Collection
          - General images
          - Farming in Leelanau but not on island
          - Food Preservation
          - Island Farming
          - Logging
          - Native Americans
          - Shipwrecks and Storms
          - Steam Ships and Schooners
        - Mrs. Roe-related
        - Paula Jones Collection
        - Shalda Family Collection
      - South Manitou 1925, 1938, .ZIP file
        - General images
        - Jack Barratt Collection
    - Other Areas (Non-Sleeping Bear Dunes Region) 1866-1957, .ZIP file
      - Doan Family
      - Scott Family
      - Van Zoeren Farm, Vriesland
  - Video Recordings 1995-2010
    The Video Recordings subseries (13.7 GB, 1995-2010) contains oral history interviews in video formats, often in the context of a tour of a particular area or farm, as well as videos of various historic sites in the Port Oneida area. Files are arranged by interviewee or topic.
    - Port Oneida Sites 2010, .ZIP file
    - Barratt, Jack tour interview 2005, .MP4 file
    - Basch, Laura
      - Area Tour interview, Parts 1 and 2 1995, .MP4 files
      - Photos interview, Parts 1, 2, and 3 1995, .MP4 files
    - Mason, Lorraine interview, .MP4 file
    - Olsen Family Reunion interview 2007, .MP4 file
    - Thoreson, Leonard
      - Area Tour interview 2005, .MP4 file
      - Farm Tour interview 2006, .MP4 file
  - Genealogies 2009-2010, .ZIP file
    The Genealogies subseries (1.6 GB, 2009-2010) consists of genealogical charts for Port Oneida area families and the DeKorne family. It includes both genealogy software files in GenoPro and GEDCOM formats as well as family trees exported from the software as PDF files.
    - DeKorne family genealogy files and family tree
    - Port Oneida families genealogy files and family trees
  - Census & Cemetery Records 1920, 2006, .ZIP file
    The Census and Cemetery Records subseries (19.9 MB, 1920 and 2006) contains an image of 1920 Census record for the Glen Arbor township and cemetery record information for the Maple Grove Cemetery and the St. Philip Neri Cemetery in Empire.
    - Image of census record for Glen Arbor Township 1920
    - Lists of cemetery record information for Maple Grove Cemetery and St. Philip Neri Cemetery in Empire 2006
  - Historic Maps 1881-2009, .ZIP file
    The Historic Maps subseries (101 MB, 1881-2009) includes images of maps showing Leelanau County, Glen Arbor, the Port Oneida area, etc.
    - Leelanau County Atlas 1881 Atlas
    - Platt Book, circa 1920
    - Plat Book 1961
    - Port Oneida area maps 2009
  - Other Resources 1995, 2007-2011
    The Other Resources subseries (37.4 MB, 1995 and 2007-2011) contains collected written and compiled resources on the Sleeping Bear Dunes region, and in particular the Port Oneida area.
    - Introduction by Tom Van Zoeren 2011, .DOC file and .DOCX file
    - Miscellaneous documents 1995, 2007-2010, .ZIP file